Okay, so our player sprites looking really good.
So I think it's time to move on to our tree and foliage sprite.
Now this process is also going to be quite similar to our car obstacle sprite from our previous game.
So we can take that knowledge and implement that here.
And that's what programming is all about, using what you've learned and applying it in different scenarios
to solve different problems.
The first thing, let's click this button here so we can see our sprite again.
Now we could go ahead and build all this code from scratch.
But I want to show you something cool.
If you look down at the bottom of your screen, you will see that there is this button that says backpack.
And if you click it, you'll see it opens up this window at the bottom.
And basically what this is, is a place where you can store scripts and reuse them in other places.
Because remember how I said earlier how creating reusable code is so important?
Well, here you're going to see why.
So if we move back over to our traffic race again and then to our car sprite, what we can do is open
up our backpack and looking at the script here that controls the cloned cars, making them glide to
the bottom of the screen.
What we can do is drag the script over here into our backpack, and as we also need the script that
creates the clones, we can grab that too.
But before we do so, first remove this block from the weight statement, then drag it in.
Now we can put this block back.
This way we don't have all this code that we don't need in our backpack.
Now moving back to our ski game, you might just need to close and reopen the backpack to refresh it.
And there it is.
Now all we need to do is drag it on in and we can do the same for the script.
And there you go.
You will see here that brings with it variables, which is movement and speed.
And you can actually keep that as we will use them in this game.
And before we edit the script, let's shed some light on another key programming principle compartmentalization.
Yes, I know it sounds like a big word, but it's an important one.
So let's try to understand what this means with a real world visualization.
Imagine your game as a large, bustling, busy city.
Now, in a city, you wouldn't just jumble up the homes and the offices and the industries and the parks
all in one space, would you?
Instead, you would zone them into districts or compartments.
You'd have residential zones and industrial zones and business zones and parks, etc...
This is the essence of compartmentalization and coding.
By segmenting our code into distinct sections or compartments, each dedicated to a specific function
or task.
And by doing this, we achieve two major benefits.
First, our code becomes much more organized and manageable, just as city officials would only need
to review and manage a specific district for any changes, developers can focus on individual compartments
of code without getting all overwhelmed by the entirety of the code.
And secondly, this approach greatly helps in creating reusable code.
Now, when code sections are compartmentalized effectively, they can often be picked up and placed
into another project.
But maybe just some minimal adjustments.
Just like we reused the obstacle code from our traffic racer game.
And on this point, I want to show you how we could do the same for our Traffic Racer game to give it
a quick upgrade.
So if we go to our main player sprite, open up our backpack and then drag this script into it, we
can then move back to our Traffic Racer game, refresh the backpack, and then drag this script into
our main car sprite.
And then we can remove all these change X blocks from the script like so.
Now it will change X by our movement direction, just like with our ski game and hitting play.
Well, that's somewhat works.
The only problem is our car direction looks a bit weird.
So to fix it we can also just insert these movement direction variables into our point direction.
So this way our car faces the way it's turning.
So clicking play once more.
Well that's a lot better.
And it adds a whole new element to our game.
And it was so quick.
That's the power of reusable code and compartmentalization.
But with all that said, let's move back to our skiing game and also to our tree sprite.
So now all we need to do is edit the script a bit so it works better for this game, just like we did
with the traffic game.
So we can change switch costumes to pick between 1 and 11 and that's how many costumes we have.
Then we can remove all this as we no longer have lanes to worry about, but we can just put in a pick
random for our X input and have it between -220 and 220.
And then we can remove this movement speed variable from the code and just set it to minus nine.
And then we can set the size to 50 as that's our current size.
And finally we can remove the if condition that makes the car vroom sound.
So giving that a go.
And as you can see, our trees come down nicely and it's starting to feel a bit more like skiing.
However, there is one problem which you may have noticed is that the stone sprite seems to get stuck
on the bottom of the screen.
Well, we can fix this by going into the costume editor using the selection tool and clicking on our
rock, and then dragging it higher up.
Now you'll notice that it should stop getting stuck, but if yours is still getting stuck, just move
it up a bit higher.
And the same for any other sprites that are getting stuck, just keep moving them higher until they
stop getting stuck.
But there you have it.
We are skiing down some fresh slopes here, looking like an absolute natural you are.